A characterization of the issues we're having making the LCD display anything after revision 509
Creator: Matt McKnett
$Author$
$Date$
$Revision$

Problem:
In revision 508, test_lcd.c and MuddCLib.c could be compiled and simulated such that the LCD printed at least one character and followed a move instruction.  After changes made in revision 509, the LCD no longer prints any text or displays the cursor.  The changes made to test_lcd.c were trivial, to reflect the change in the delay1000count function name.  The changes made to MuddCLib.c were:

	- Creating a delay1clock function, and calling this function within delay1000clock (which was renamed from delay1KTCYx).
	- In initLCD, instead of sending instruction 0x14 and then clearing the screen, we clear the screen and then send 0x06.
	- We add a delay1clock(10) to dispChar after writing the data to the LCD.
	- We add a conditional delay to sendInst - if the instructino is a clear or a move home, delay1clock(200); otherwise, delay1clock(10).


Solution:
I have already investigated the change in initLCD, and I do not believe it is the problem.  I suspect, then, that the problem is with the new delay functions, but I cannot guess what it is.  The only difference between the old delay1KTCYx function and delay1clock is that delay1clock compares cycle_count to 0 instead of using "while(cycle_count)" to mean "while(cycle_count != 0)".  Also, delay1000clock has a multiply in the parameter for calling delay1clock.  These seem to be trivial and non-issues, so I don't know how they could be the culprits.

The issue may also be that our timing is in the wrong place.  Prior to this revision, we were having issues with the LCD not displaying anything after the initial *.  We suspected that it was because sending the LCD the "clear" command meant we needed to wait a 1.5ms or so.  We then added these delay functions to the instruction and display methods to try to alleviate that problem, and after that nothing displayed (and the cursor did not appear).  The strangest part is the disappearance of the cursor, which indicates to me that either the instruction 0x08 is being sent somewhere or 0x0C (not to be confused with 0xC0, which is a move to the second line).  

So, the issue is probably with timing or the timing functions themselves.